Stephen Gbolagade

PROFILE

Experienced Frontend Engineer with +4 years of experience in web development using React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, GraphQL and CSS frameworks. Proven in team leadership, architecture decisions, pixel-perfect UI delivery, and backend integration. Passionate about crafting user-friendly web experiences.

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer, HOMESILO

Apr 2021 - Present

Nigeria

- · Led a team of 6 to build a successful Startup MVP, resulting in 50+ initial waitlist sign-ups within the first month.
- · Played a key role in product architecture and decision-making.
- Contributed to major features:
 - Achieved pixel-perfect UI implementations.
 - · Created usable components and hooks.
 - · Connected frontend to backend services via GraphQL and REST.
 - · Integrated payment gateways.
 - Implemented WebSocket chat functionality.

Web Developer, AG CONSULTING & MEDIA, Inc.

Sept 2021 – Jun 2022

USA, Remote

- Redesigned the agency's website using WordPress, resulting in a significant increase in conversion rates compared to the previous version.
- · Managed and maintained the website while concurrently building custom landing pages for event campaigns and live streams.
- · Assisted the founder in talent outsourcing.
- · Converted UI designs into responsive websites.

Web Developer, INTODOORS, LLC

Sept 2019 - Jan 2021

USA. Remote

- Built, deployed, and maintained custom web pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Worked on the primary real estate web application using WordPress, HTML, and CSS.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Integrated payment gateways and MLS/IDX for property listings.
- · Managed and maintained the entire suite of marketing tools, including Yoast SEO, Google Search Console, Analytics, and Google Business.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Freelance, FIVERR

Dec 2016 - Aug 2021

- Successfully completed over 70 projects in web development, SEO, and Digital Marketing
- · Got 68 five-star ratings.

Frontend Developer, OPENWAVER

Apr 2023 - May 2023

- Developed and delivered the web3 startup's website using Nextjs, Material UI and Tailwind.
- Integrated native blogging system using SANITY CMS and Groaq API.

CONTACT

Location Ile-Ife, Nigeria.

solgade01@gmail.com **Email**

Linkedin /in/solgade **Portfolio** stephengade.com

GitHub astephengade

Tel +234 81 6454 0355

Dev.to dev.to/stephengade

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript (ES6+)
- TypeScript
- React.js (with Next.js)
- Vue.js
- HTML & CSS
- GraphQL
- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- Material UI
- Styled Components
- Bulma

Additional Skills

- SEO
- Content Writing
- WordPress
- Shopify
- WIX

Tools and services

- Firebase
- Vercel, Netlify, Render

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Analytical Skills
- Adaptability
- Creativity
- Time Management

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

BSc in Applied Geophysics.